the Internet is a massive part of all of our lives
互联网是我们生活中不可或缺的一部分
have you ever stopped to wonder
你是否曾经停下来思考
whether there's a large group of volunteers
是否会有一大群志愿者
putting in their time and effort
投入他们的时间和精力
to help make it all work
来帮助整个互联网运转起来
I got involved with Apache from it's very first day
我从Apache成立的第一天起就参与其中
this thing called the web in 1992
在1992这个东西被称为网络
felt extremely disruptive
给人们带来了极大的颠覆性的体验
not only fresh not only interesting
不仅新鲜不仅有趣而
but like this could be the foundation of something big
且它可能成为一些大型事物的基础
and it was addictive to be a part of that
成为其中一员令人上瘾
and to make all this work we're using
为了使一切运行起来，我们用
all the web software of the time
上了当时能用的所有网络软件
there was a web server from the University of
有一个来自伊利诺伊大学的网络服务器
Illinois called the NCSA web server
名叫NCSA的网络服务器
that seemed to do a pretty decent job
那似乎是一份体面的工作
and like all Internet software at the
就好像当时所有网络软件
time you got the source code to it and
你都拿到了源码
the presumption was that if you used it
假设你你正在使用它
and you found something wrong
并发现一些异常
or you wanted to add a feature and you coded it
或者你想添加一个新特性，你编写好代码
up well why not just contribute it back
为什么不将它贡献回去
right why not
为什么不呢
I mean why keep a bug fix to yourself
我的意思是为什么只给自己修复错误
right and I found this amazing
对吧！我惊讶地发现
community emerge other people contributing
社区出现了其它人的贡献
other people fixing bugs and adding features
其它人在修复错误并添加特性
and and it wasn't like
并且不像是
somebody from this institution somebody from that company
机构自己的人，公司的人
it was individuals it was people
而是个人，是人
[Music]
I was introduced to Apache by brian behlendorf
我被brian behlendorf介绍给Apache
it was back in 1995
那是在1995
I was doing a PhD working a robotic telescope
我当时正在做博士，研究机器人望远镜
and I was controlling it via via the internet
我正在通过网络控制它
and so at the time
与此同时
we were using the NCSA web server
我正在使用NCSA网络服务器
and we had some issues with that server
我发现那台服务器的一些问题
so I created a number of patches to kind of
所以我创建了几个补丁
get it to work really well with with  the telescope
使得它真正地和望远镜配合起来
and as part of that
作为其中的一部分
I'd found some security issues and fixed those as well
我发现一些安全问题并修复这些问题
and so having met Brian
当我遇到Brian
he has a fellow web administrator
他有一个同伴，一个网站管理员
I'd sent him those patches and he said hey
我将那些补丁发送给他，他说嘿
you know we've got a group coming together
你知道我们有个小组聚在一起
who are all sharing patches based on that web server
这些人都在分享那个网络服务器的补丁
would you like to join it
你愿意加入吗
I was supposed to en to
我本打算去，嗯，去
analyze satellite images about LG
分析LG卫星图像
about about green stuff in the sea
海洋中绿色的东西
and see what the sea temperatures were so based on satellite pictures
基于卫星图片，去看海水的温度是多少
but that data was
但是那些数据
really sort of like cumbersome to process
要去处理，真的有些麻烦
so I was in the lab
那时我正在
in the north of Italy of the European Commission and
欧洲委员会意大利北部的实验室里
it was just not working it was difficult
就是分析不出结果，很难
but I'd seen a few years earlier
但早在几年之前我见过
at CERN at the particle physics lab that
在CERN的粒子物理实验室
there was a wonderful data server
有一个很棒的数据服务器
which came about what we call a web server today
它就是我们今天所说的网络服务器
which made a lot of this
它使得大量的
hope like data processing easier so like
数据处理更加简单
I found this community around me off of
我发现这个社区，我周围
people like-minded and an actually that went
都是志趣相投的人
went on quite quite pleasantly and
进行得相当地愉快并且
really rather nice for a little while
真的好了一阵
but then suddenly sort like things started to change
但是突然事情开始发生改变
so one day an email
一天一封邮件
goes to the developers list
发到了开发者列表
for this NCSA web server
关于NCSA网络服务器
from those student developers at the University of Illinois going
来自伊利诺伊大学的大学生开发者正准备离开
hey guys sorry about this but
嘿，伙伴们，对于这件事非常抱歉
we've we're not going to be working anymore
我们将不再维护
on this web server software
这个网络服务器
because we are we've all gotten jobs
因为我们都找到了工作
with this brand new company called Netscape
在一个全新的，叫网景的公司
so we were left dependent upon
所以我们离开了
this open-source web server that
这个开源的网络服务器
no one was coding no one was maintaining
不再有人编码和维护
and we realized that we were in a pretty
我们意识到我们正处于相当
precarious position
危险的情形中
and in a rare kind of fit of foresight
出于罕见的先见之明
we decided to look at the copyright license on the code and
我们决定去查看代码的版权许可
it basically said here's this code do
版权许可基本上是说给你代码
whatever you want with it just give us credit
你可以随意改动它，仅需要给我们认可
when you take it somewhere else
当你在别的地方使用它时
and you create a derivative work from it
你可以从中创建衍生作品
and don't blame us when it breaks and
但是当它不工作时不要责怪我们
this don't
不要
blame when it breaks thing you know and you're
责怪当它弄坏其它东西的时候，就是说你知道
on your own but good luck but here's code
你要对这些代码负责，祝你好运，给你代码
was this amazing insight
真是令人惊讶的见解
it was like alright we can we can you know
就好像是，那好吧，你知道
we could do this ourselves we were lucky
我们可以自己维护，我们足够幸运
enough to collect a group of people over a mailing list
在邮件列表里聚集了一组人
to coordinate and consolidate
去协作和加固
some of the patches and the ideas
一些补丁以及
and the features and the improvements we wanted to see
想法、特性以及一些期望见到的
in the own NCSA web server
NCSA服务器的改进
and use that to create
并使用那些去构建
the Apache web server sort of like a
Apache网络服务器，有点像
phoenix rising out of the ashes
凤凰从灰烬中起飞
we decided to inherit that same thinking
我们决定继承同样的想法
that same mentality of well
同样的心态
let's work together voluntarily let's combine our efforts
让我们自愿一起合作、共同努力
let's put do this at a new home
让我们在一个新的家继续
and we needed a name we just called it new httpd at first
我们需要一个名字，我们起初叫它新httpd
and and i suggested the
后来我建议叫
name apache partly because you know that
Apache 部分原因是，你知道
the most web technologies at the time
那时候大多数的由我们推出的
that we're launching were being called cyber this or spider
web技术都以网络或蜘蛛来命名
that or you know something on those themes
或者，你知道，与这些主题相关的名称
and I was like I need something more interesting
我想我需要的东西是更加有趣
a little more romantic and not to be a
有点浪漫而不是
cultural appropriator or anything like
文化占用者或类似的东西
that but I just seen a documentary about
我刚刚看过一个纪录片有关
Geronimo and kind of the last days of
Geronimo和讲述的是类似于
the Native American tribe called the Apaches
一个叫，Apache的美国原住民部落的末日
right who has to come to  the invasion
对吧！他们遭到了
from from the West from from from the United States
来自美国西部居民的入侵
and they were the
他们是最后一个放弃
last tribe to give up their territory
自己领土的部落
and for me that kind of almost romantically
这对我来说几乎是浪漫地
represented what I felt
代表我的感受
we were doing with this web server project
我们正在做的网络服务器项目
which was you know at the time Microsoft
你知道在那个时候,微软
owned 95% of the desktops all they had
占据了95%的台式机,它们都需要
to do was come up with a browser and a
配备一个浏览器和服务器
server and if they owned both links well
如果他们占据了这一链接的两端
it was kind of game over
游戏就结束了
back then we were really leading a fight
那时我们确实领导了一场战争
leading a battle against the the FUD the
领导一场与FUD的斗争
fear uncertainty in doubt of what
这是一种对开源到底是什么的
open-source was about
恐惧、不确定和怀疑
there were a lot of very very large companies just not
有很多非常大的公司并不
really familiar with what open-source
真正了解什么是开源
was about and some very very strong
还有一些非常强大的
powerful companies who were very
公司非常反对
antagonistic towards it and so as kind
开源因这件事，因此作为
of a protest vote we adopted the name
一个抗议投票，我们采用了名字
Apache other people said that makes for
Apache，有人说这
a good name from a romantic point of
从浪漫的角度来说确是一个好名字
view but also like a good pun that
而且像是一个很好的双关
pieces of code that were being given to it by this group of people
一群人给它贡献一小部分代码
they were called patches back in the day they're
那时被称为打补丁，现在被
called pull requests now but back then
称为拉取请求，那个时候
they were called patches and so it's a
它们被称为补丁，所以它是一个
patchy software because that's a pun on
拼凑的软件，它是对于事实的双关
the fact that it was made up of patches which I love
它是由很多补丁组成，这也是我喜欢的
so for us creating a software program
对于我们来说创造一个软件项目
creating an open-source foundation and
创建开源基金会
creating knowledge about what open-source was about
创建关于开源项目的知识
was sort of like a Trident battle
就像是一场三叉戟之战
the idea that  we won in this fight
我们在这场战争中获胜
to make open-source the the de-facto way that
使得开源成为一种人们
people develop software
开发软件的方法
you know it was such a long shot for so long
你知道它需要很长的过程
the Apache web server became within
我认为 Apache 网络服务器
less than I think about six months
在不到六个月
or less than a year the most popular
或一年的时间
and widely used web server in the world
成为最受欢迎的、在世界上广泛使用的网络服务器
and it took market share away from other commercial products
它从其它商业产品手里拿到了市场份额
some of these companies didn't
非常明显这些公司
really didn't really like that
非常不喜欢它
Apache just its market share exploded
Apache 市场份额出现爆发增长
right - over 65 percent of the websites
对吧！超过65%的网站
out there running Apache I mean
运行着Apache，我的意思是
everybody from the Vatican to the FBI to
所有人，从梵蒂冈到联邦调查局
all of our web sites and then
到我们所有的网站
finally at 98 we also started to get knocks on
终于在98 年，我们开始受到一些
our door from certain large companies
大公司的拜访
in particular IBM initially
特别是最初的IBM
but also starting to hear from like people like
当然也开始听到来自
HP and Sun and and even Microsoft who
HP和Sun 公司的人声音，甚至Microsoft
started to notice not only the market
也开始注意到，不仅是市场
shared numbers not only their own
份额数，不仅是他们自己的
efforts to build web server technology
努力去构建网络服务技术
not cracking the market share numbers
没有打破当前的市场份额
and also realizing that this license
还注意到这个许可证书
this a copyright license we used was
我们采用的版权许可是
something that they could work with and
他们也可以参与的
when we had conversations with these
当我们与这些公司交谈后
companies saying that you know we're
这些公司说我们
just a bunch of dudes on a mailing list
只是在邮件列表的一群人
was not good enough not good enough for
还不够好，对他们来说还不够
them I could enough for us and
对我们自己来说也不够好
by summer of 99 we had started the Apache Software Foundation
到了99年夏天，我们开始成立Apache 软件基金会
so when the Apache Software Foundation was formed
当基金会的成立的时候
I really saw it as
我真地把它看作是
umbrella of one product and I never really imagined
一个产品的保护，我从未真正地想过
at that time there would be hundreds of projects
在哪个时候会有上百个项目
that want to come under the same umbrella
希望在同一个伞下
in the older days the the easy statistic was to
在更早的时候简单的统计表明
say that nine out of every ten websites
十个里有九个网站
that you went to were powered in some way
你访问的的网站是以某种方式由
for the Apache web server
Apache网络服务器提供的
but these days entire new industries big data things
但是最近整个新产业、大数据
around machine learning and processing
围绕着机器学习、流式处理
and streaming these all exists in the Apache Software Foundation
这些都在Apache 软件基金会
and are the open source projects that drive those
他们都是由开源项目驱动
entire industries so it's really hard to
整个产业,真的很难
say just in any one statistic anymore
再仅以一个统计去衡量
how large the foundation has become
基金变得有多大
with more than 300 projects
它拥有超过300个项目
it's really hard to wrap your head around the whole thing
要你去理解所有的事情真的很难
I never leave the home without this helpful t-shirt
我绝不离开家没有这个非常合意的短袖
so the project's Hadoop
项目Hadoop
Mahout    Geode    Victo    CloudStack    Spark
Cassandra  Big  Hive  Zookeeper  Cumulus  Sqoop
Flink that's a big data ecosystem
Flink 是一个大数据生态
Java projects Maven Dart Yetus CouchDB
Java项目Maven  Dart   Yetus CouchDB
CloudStack is pretty cool  httpd
CloudStack非常酷 ,httpd
the one that actually gave us the Apache Software Foundation yeah
正是它创造了Apache软件基金会,没错!
so some times it's really hard to understand the
所以有时候非常难理解
impact of a lot of what we're doing at Apache
我们在Apache所做的大量的事产生的影响
right because it's not something that you see on television
对吧！真不是你在电视上看到的那样
people depend more on the ASF
人们对ASF的依赖
than they realize
超出他们的想象
a lots of the time when you think you're just
很多时候当你以为你只是在
accessing a website you're using ASF software somewhere in there
访问一个网站,你正在使用某个地方的ASF软件
like it's all like every everywhere and everything
就好像是无处不在
right it's in every mobile phone how the
对吧！它存在于每一台移动电话中，
banking systems get together I mean if
存在于银行系统中
you're a cap or if you order a meal
如果你是一个警察或者如果你去点餐
open-source is everywhere
开源无处不在
you know it's in your fridge it's in your telephone it's in your car
你知道,它存在于你的冰箱、电话、汽车
I'm an electric bike software
即使是一辆电动自行车
I'm sure there's even some open-source software in that
我很确信都会包含开源软件
we have someone who
我们有些人
works at a National Space Agency
在国家航天局工作
who is confirmed that some of the modules from Apache Commons
他确认一些Apache Commons的模块
were on a satellite that was sent into space
被用在了发送到太空的卫星上
which is pretty cool
这太酷了
that there are patchy committer
一些补丁的贡献者
we've written code running in space today
我们写的代码在太空运行
well I hope this headlights still there
太好了,我希望头顶的光仍在
control some huge engines and robots
控制大型发动机和机器人
Apple who use it as their infrastructure layer for Siri
Apple使用它作为Siri的基础层
Apache foundation has changed the way
Apache基金已经改变了
we do open source inside Alibaba
Alibaba内部参与开源的方式
and for many developers in China in general
和许多中国的开发者
as soon as are something intimately involved networks
一旦一些东西涉及到网络
mobile a web browser that will basically
手机，一个网页浏览器基本上是由
layers layers of apache software to process
一层层的Apache软件去处理文档
documents to process xml's who have
处理成xml文档， 通过哪些
complex who have API I mean you just  name it
复杂的你能直接说出名字的API
the Panama papers were analyzed
对巴拿马文件的分析
using Apache products that's huge
就是使用的Apache产品,文件非常巨大
NASA uses Apache products in space
NASA在太空上使用Apache的产品
dead somebody that they've
人在死前最后几个小时他们
used Apache software within the last hour
仍在使用Apache软件
and they have they have
他们会的，他们会的
because not only our projects particularly
因为不仅是我们的项目特别地
widespread but the spread of projects is
广泛传播而且项目的传播
enormous it's almost certain that
非常广泛,可以确信的是
they've used some Apache software
人们使用了一些Apache 软件
not knowing it not necessarily seeing it
但是并不知道它,也不必看见它
but it's almost certainly there
但是它确实就在那里
and it's unless you've been asleep for the last
但是它除非你在最后的八个小时睡着了
eight hours it's really really hard to go
会非常难以生存
in a modern technological scenes
在现代技术场景下
more than just a short period of time
仅一会
without using some apache software
不使用Apache软件
when it's something now you know
现在，你知道
people can touch and interact with their phones and their cars
人们触摸并与自己的手机、汽车交互
anyway you realize all of that's open-source software
无论如何，你察觉到了这背后开源软件的存在
and it's like wow okay
这就像是，哇！好吧！
this is something that's truly changed the world
它们才是真正改变世界的东西
[Music]
so what is open-source
所以开源是什么 ？
why is open-source so important to the community
为什么开源对于Apache社区如此重要
everybody being in a large sandbox
聚集在这个大沙箱中的每个人
and instead of everyone going off
并不是
to different corners and sides
分散在各处
and building their own little castles
建造他们自己的小城堡
all those people in that singular sandbox
而是大家聚集在这个沙箱里
actually working together on a really really cool big sandcastle
真正地齐心协力，共同搭建一个极棒的沙堡
interestingly enough
有趣的是
that sandbox analogy was actually given at multiple times
这个沙箱比拟出我们说过很多次
when we still had a lot of discussion
当时我们就讨论了很多
about what open-source even means right
关于开源究竟意味着什么的，对吧！
you come from a commercial background
你来自商业公司
and you think about open-source you think well hey
你认为开源很不错，嘿！
it can't work but it does
虽然它不能赚钱，但它很有用
that they just don't understand at the moment that
只是他们当时不理解
why is somebody giving away something that
为什么会有人提供的
is free but is way better than
一些免费产品却远比
the things they have to pay a lot of money for
他们花很多钱买的东西还好
we give away software that is really cool
我们免费提供了很多很酷
and does amazing things
很优异的产品
why do we give it away
为什么我们免费提供？
because that's what we do
因为那就是我们所做的
because the impact of open source is
是因为开源的影响在于
that openness the ability for anyone to
开放性使得任何人可以
come and use and consume and contribute
使用、消费和贡献
and so when I first sort of joined the project
当我第一次加入这个项目的时候
it was sort of like you know who's in charge
正如你知道的,谁负责？
there's nobody charge who's gonna tell me what to do
没人负责，谁会来告诉我该做什么？
nobody's gonna tell me what to do
没人会告诉我该做什么
you choose
你自己选择
what you think is value to the projects and the community
你认为对项目和社区有益的事情
so there's a lot of sort of
有许多种类的
non-technical education and awareness
那些非技术层面的教育和意识形态
that goes on and needs to continue going
正在发展并需要继续进行
on so that the people who write the checks
使得付钱的人
and the people who run the businesses
和经营企业者
can understand what open source is
能明白开源是什么
it's difficult I think for
我觉得对于
a lot of older people
很多年龄大点的人
especially the the more corporate type people to understand
特别是企业里的人来说，是很难理解
why a really talented programmer who
为什么一个有才华的程序员
could command a lot of money by doing
他可以通过为公司工作
their work for for companies would be
赚到很多钱
willing to volunteer their time to do it basically for free
却愿意自愿花时间去做开源,它基本上是免费的
I mean why would you want to do that
我的意思是为什么你想要做这件事
and for me it's an acknowledgement of
what I see was the old hacker culture
对于我而言,是出于对我所见到的古老黑客文化的认可
I mean developers
我的意思是开发者
coders contributors are artists
写代码的人、贡献者都是艺术家
and I think all artists want to share
我认为所有的艺术家都想分享
their the results of their craft
他们的技术成果
they want to work with aligned people
他们想与志同道合的人一起工作
they want to hone their skills
他们想磨练技能
there's sort of a pride of art
他们有种艺术的自豪感
when you when you rise from simply being a coder that
当你从单纯地使它工作起来的编程人员
makes something work to actually
creating a thing of beauty and it it may
逐渐变为创造美的事物时
seem a little pretentious but but it is
看起来有些自命不凡 但这是
it is still a great desire you know
一个很伟大的愿望
when I create something I want it
当我创造某个东西的时候
I want it to be beautiful as well as functional if
我希望它美观又实用 如果
everyone knows that I did a particular piece of code
所有人知道那段是我写的代码
then I'm a lot more careful
我会更加仔细地
to make it good and if it's just
去写好它,如果它仅仅
something that's going into a
是一些没有人能看到的
proprietary thing that no one ever sees
私有项目代码
then I can be a little sloppier
我就可以稍微草率点
we also have to work with lots of close software
我也不得不用到一些闭源软件
and it just sucks it makes our job it
它太烂了,不仅会让程序难度增加
makes our job harder it's hard to debug
还不易于调试
how to reason about you don't know what's going on
不好推理,你不知道接下来会怎么样
and with your Apache Software Foundation
在Apache软件基金会
you can look at every piece of code
你可以看到所有的代码
and that makes things much easier
使得事情变得更简单
and you work together with a bunch of people
你和大家一起工作
who chose these products
他们都在用这些产品
usually to collaborate
通常你们可以相互协作
and they weren't forced to do this
他们不是被强制去做这件事的
a lot of the software early on that I built
很多我早期构建的软件
I would put a license on it saying please use this
我会在许可里面写到，请使用它
I'd be happy to do it but if you're
我非常乐意这样做，但如果你
gonna make money on it come back to me
使用它赚钱，请找我
and let's make a deal
让我们达成协议
and I have to say that really prevented the use of that software
我必须承认这确实阻碍了软件的的使用
later I decided just to say
后来我决定
I'm not gonna fight about it
不再反对它
therefore why should I argue about it
因此为什么还要为此争论呢？
let's just put  in a public domain
让我们仅使用一个公共领域许可
I had no idea that  the effects of that
我不知道它会有什么影响
but that caused my software to be massively used
但是这使得我的软件被广泛地使用
and that really surprised me
真的让我感到惊讶
that that I would get more back by letting go more freely
通过这种更加自由的方式,我将得到更多的回报
and then when I found out about
后来当我发现
the rationales behind Apache and the license
Apache和许可证后面的逻辑
and things like that it really clicked
这样的事让我顿悟到
it does enable people to use your
它使得人们能使用你的开源软件
open-source software without giving anything back
无需任何回报
and we're okay with that
我们对此表示同意
we acknowledge that at the very very
在一开始的时候 我们就承认
beginnings that a permissive license
授权的许可证书
allowed people to use without giving back
允许人们使用不必给与回报
but we saw the importance of having that capability
我们看到了拥有这种能力的重要性
because at least for us
至少对我们来说
was better to encourage people to
鼓励人们贡献回来
contribute back rather than force them
而不是强制他们贡献是一种更好的方式
you see things like the GPL that are
你可以看到像GPL
you know like these pure open-source
你知道,类似的纯开源许可证书
licenses without any kind of restrictions
没有任何限制
right you know it's like
对吧!你知道,它就好像
other than it's like you can't commercialize it
就像,你不可以用于商业
you can't close sources
你不可以闭源
you know the the LGPL is even worse right
你知道 LGPL更加糟糕,对吧！
because then now your code is LGPL by proxy
通过开源协议传递，你的代码也会变成LGPL
and you know it's like the apache license
你知道，像Apache许可证
is so open that
是如此开放
that's gonna get people to come in and work on
以至于吸引到人们参与其中
it and you see that all the time in the apache community itself
在Aapche社区，你一直能看见这样的事情
the license that we have apache license
我们拥有的Apache许可证书
is one of the most business-friendly licenses out there
是对商业最友好的证书之一
which enables you to actually leverage that software
它使你可以真正地利用此软件
in all sorts of  different ways to create businesses around it
以各种不同的方式去打造和它相关的商业
that very interesting combination that
它是一个非常有趣的组合
dynamics between builders and intrapreneurs is that what
正是构建者和内部企业家动态关系
makes ASF very very successful
使得ASF非常非常成功
and we need to try to communicate that value proposition
我们需要尝试将这种价值主张
to both developers and entrepreneurs
传达给开发者和内部企业家
your software's where you know
你知道你的软件在这里
they've got these huge communities
他们获得了庞大的社区
huge amounts of you know support not
从中得到大量的支持
only from individuals like us
不仅仅是来自像我这样的个人
but you know from big big companies
你知道,是来自的大公司
you know using this and feeding back into the community
你知道,使用它并反馈回社区
and to me that's what it's all about
对我来说这没关系
right because I never want to be
对吧！因为我从未想过成为
the smartest guy in the room right
房间里最聪明的人，对吧！
and when you try to closed-source something
当你尝试闭源一些东西
or try to make it just fully open
或使它完全开放
you're gonna drive away those people who want
你会赶走那些
to actually have that sense of community
真正有社区意识的人
it always felt like the most smart people
actually everywhere else you know
总是感觉别的地方有更加聪明的人你知道
they across the globe
他们遍布全球
and unless you keep in touch with the open-source
除非你与开源社区保持联系
communities you basically don't get to experience
你基本不会体验到
all of the innovation that just out there
所有创新都出之那里
when working with people
当你和一些
that are so much better than yourself
比你优秀很多的人一起工作
you learn a lot you work
你会从中学到很多
with people that you know work at Facebook at Google
和在Facebook Google 工作的人、
developers from IBM NASA engineers in
和来自IBM的开发者 NASA的工程师、
various projects engineers from the NSA
和来自NSA不同项目的工程师
and you rub elbows with these guys and
一起工作交流时
you learn and you grow
你会学习并成长起来
and you become more than who you would have become
你变得比原来优秀得多
if you weren't part of this
如果你不是他们中的一份子
joining force with open-source effort is rewarding
参与开源是有回报的
you give a little you take back way more
你付出的很少,得到很多
so that's really what I want to share
所以这正是我想要分享的
especially with developers or companies in China
特别是与来自中国的开发者或公司分享
that don't be afraid to give to share
不要害怕去付出、分享
you would get more out of it
你会从中得到更多
Trust is hard to achieve
信任很难达成
especially with people you've never met
特别是和你从未见过的人
but if you push yourself out of that comfort zone
但是如果你将自己推出舒适区
a little bit the balancing act there
并且把握好尺度
I still believe in 2019 the balancing act of trusting
现在我仍旧相信对信任的平衡把握
more than you might
超过你的想象
otherwise feel comfortable doing still
否则做感觉舒适的事
ends up with not only better outcomes for you
不仅对你来说会有更好的结果
but at better outcomes for everyone
而且还会给所有人带来更好的结果
one of the things that we are really battling with nowadays
如今，我们正在抗争的事情之一
is just the size and scale of the organization
是组织的大小和规模
growth is not bad
增长不是坏事
it's the the uninformed growth  it's the unconstrained growth
突如其来的、没有限制的增长才是
we realized that at our current rate of of growth
我们意识到当前的增长速度
we may be in a little bit of difficulty
可能面临一些困难
in terms of funding the operations
就资金运作方面
so the the biggest
最大的
challenge basically is making sure that
挑战基本上是要确保
the foundation can continue to exist as we grow
随着我们成长，基金会能继续存在
we have to make sure that
我们必须确保
we can keep funding this organization into the future
我们可以在未来继续为组织提供资金
because those communities that
因为那些
we invite to participate in our sandbox
我们邀请进去我们沙箱的社区
they actually expect quite a bit of support
他们实际上期望更多的支持
that we are only capable of giving
我们只能提供这些支持
because of the wonderful sponsorships
因为作为一个组织
that we are receiving as an organization
我们得到了很好的赞助
so growth at all costs is a toxic concept
所以不惜一切的增长是有害的观念
I mean there's only one organism in nature
我的意思是自然界中只有一个生物
that grows at any cost
是不顾一切的增长
and that's cancer
那就是癌症
right in the modern world  in the corporate world
没错吧！在现代世界、企业界
growth is kind of considered fundamental
增长被认为是必须的
it's like no you
就好像是，不是吧你
if you're not growing by 2% or 20% given year
如果你一年没有增长2% 或者20%
if you're in fact shrinking or just
实际上如果你萎缩或者仅
staying flat well you're a failure
保持现状，你是失败的
but we don't have those pressures in the nonprofit software world
但在一个非营利软件的世界，我们没有这些压力
we don't have to respond to that at Apache
在Apache我们不必回应这些
the impulse to grow and and to grow to
成长的冲动让
thousands of  developers impacted to
受数以千记的开发者影响的
hundreds of projects like Apache now
上百个Apache项目
has been much more out of a sense of well
已经远远超过了一般的水平
if we figured out how this should work
如果我们弄清楚了它是如何工作的
let's be advocates of that
让我们倡导它
let's help other people understand
让我们帮助其它人理解
and and share what has made things really work
分享那些真正有用的东西
i'm involved with a program at Google called Apache at Google
我参与一个Google的项目，叫Apache在Google
which is largely helping Google as an organization
它极大地帮助Google，做为一个组织
contribute to the ASF
为Apache软件基金会做贡献
I know the story is that it's all volunteers but
我知道的故事是所有的志愿者
obviously most software engineers are paid
很明显绝大多数的软件工程师都是有偿
to do their work
去做他们的工作
and the way in which they're volunteers is really that
他们成为志愿者方式实际上是
they choose to work on projects
他们选择在这些项目里工作
that give them a chance to contribute to Apache
这给他们一个为Apache做贡献的机会
yes we're trying to make a better world
没错，我们一直在努力使得世界更美好
but at the same time we we all need to make a living
但是与此同时，我们都需要谋生
so we all need to make make money
所以我们都需要赚钱
we've got organizations that need to
我们的组织需要
keep turning a profit or they'll have to shut their doors
持续盈利否则将会不得不关门
so there's obviously conflicting interests
所以显然存在利益冲突
there conflicts happen in the software development projects
冲突存在于软件开发项目之中
and sometimes these conflicts
有时候一些冲突
relate to the different type of people who contribute
与特定类型的贡献者有关
as far as the ASF concerned
就ASF所关注的而言
it's all individuals it's all volunteers
全都是个人、志愿者
the ASF does not pay anyone to develop any software
Apache基金会不会向任何人付钱去开发任何软件
however there are companies
然而会有些公司
who pay some of the employees
给员工钱
to specifically work and contribute to
去做一些特定地工作 为
to specific Apache projects
特定的Apache项目做贡献
currently we have a sort of attention between volunteer contributors
当前我们有关注到无偿贡献者
people who do it in their in their free time
他们在空业余时间为开源做贡献
and paid contributors people
与有偿的贡献者
who are being paid  by Google or IBM or Microsoft
他们由Google 或IBM或Microsoft支付费用
to contribute to our code into our communities
在社区里贡献代码
it can happen that the paid contributors
有可能有偿的贡献者
just by share volume of work
仅通过承担大量的工作
because they have 40 hours a week
因为他们一周有40小时
or more can reduce the influence of our volunteer contributors
或者更多的时间会降低无偿贡献者的影响
and can even push them out
甚至将他们挤出去
so there's this tension
所以有这样的紧张
but our volunteer contributors are the the
但是我们的无偿贡献者才是
contributors that carry our values
是承载我们价值观的贡献者
they are sort of the the cornerstone that our organization rests on
他们是组织立足的基石
and we need to find a way
我们需要寻找一种方式
to make it possible for them
使得他们能够
to to maintain a certain level of influence
维持一定水平的影响力
it can be bit difficult
去协调或做出公平的决定
to to coordinate this or to make decisions in a fair way
可能会有点困难
it's easy for the people who are working full-time
对全职工作的人员来说
to take more space in the project
投入更多精力在项目上相对容易
and maybe not leave enough time for the others
这可能无法给其他人留下足够的时间
I  could just you know fix stuff fix stuff
你是知道的，我可以修复，再修复
go go go go go and move much faster than
前进，再前进，并且超过那些
people who have just got a few hours at
只在周末有几个小时付出的人
the weekend will be it would be able to cope with it
我能够处理得当
so what I try and do
所以这就是我努力在做的事情
and I don't always get it perfectly right
而且我并不总能做到完美，对吧！
but what I try and do is
但是我仍不断地尝试着做下面的事情：
when I'm doing something that I think is going to be of
当我在做一些我认为将会引起
wider interest that people are going to
广泛关注的事情，并且是人们会希望
want to look at in more detail
看到其中更多细节、
you'll want more time to think about
想花更多的时间去思考的事情
then I sort of try and give a heads up well
我就会试着告诉大家
I'm thinking of doing something in this direction
我想在这个问题方向上做点什么，
what do you think？ And
你们觉得怎么样？
leave it a few days maybe a week
（我会）将它留在那里几天甚至一周
and then see what the responses are
然后看看会收到什么样的反馈
and then add my response, give people the time to
并给出我的回复, 再给别人时间去
respond to the point of being made
回复他们的观点
let them have the space to make their contribution
从而让他们有空间做出贡献
you know we ask a lot of
我们会问很多
the developers and other volunteers
Apache社区的开发人员和其他志愿者
in the Apache community
and ask a lot beyond just writing code
并且不仅仅要求他们编写代码
for some people this becomes their full-time job
对一部人来说这还成了他们的全职工作
and sometimes somehow they have to convince
有时他们不得不说服
their employer to let them do this right
雇主同意他们做这些
and that creates a challenge to
并且对一个项目来说，招募形成一个真正多元化的社区
recruiting a truly diverse community to the project
是非常有挑战性的
you'll find there's a lot of us
您会发现我们当中很多人
who are white dudes
都是白人男性
one of the things that I'd like to see us improve on is
我希望我们改善的事情之一就是
our diversity measures
多元化的措施
you can see I'm a woman
您可以看到我是一个女性
we don't have very many women contributing to apache software
但并没有很多女性参与到Apache软件的贡献中来
i'd like to see more women contributing to open source software
我希望看到更多女性在开源软件中的贡献
and i'd like to understand where we're failing
我想了解哪里出现了问题，
there
why we're not attracting women
为什么没办法吸引女性参与进来
and what we can do to attract more women
此外，我们能做些什么来吸引更多女性参与
I mean I'm used to being the only woman in the room
我曾经是房间里唯一的女性
that that's been part of my life for a long time
并且这个状态持续了很多年
being part of involved in
参与Apache的工作
in Apache actually opened my eyes to the fact
实际上使我大开眼界
that there was not so many women in tech
（我发现）事实上没有太多女性在科技界工作
so and one of the things that we really really came to do
因此，我们真的真的非常应该做的一件事情
is to  try and help bridge that gap
就是试着去帮助填补（女性比男生参与得少）这一差距
women in tech will leave the business much more frequently than men
在科技行业，女性离职率比男性更高
and that's true with in the apache communities as well I'm sure
在apache社区中也是如此（指女性离开社区）
and how we examine that
作为社区，我们如何调查
and how we deal with that as a community
并处理这个问题
I think we'll have a impact on future growth
会影响着未来的社区成长
I love that
我很喜爱
we're increasing our active role in
我们正在为增加多样性和更多的接触
trying to reach out and increase diversity
来努力发挥积极作用
I'm proud to call myself a game in
我很自豪能称自己
and aparted Apache Software Foundation
是Apache基金会的一员
back in 2003
在2003年
when I first joined
我最初加入Apache时
that seemed like a scary thing to say out in the open
在公开场合说出来似乎是一件令人恐惧的事情
but today I have no problems openly saying Who I am
但是今天我没有任何问题公开声明自己是谁
and being a part of this great community
并是这个伟大社区的一分子
it's really common right now
用更严肃的眼光
for projects to be looking at diversity and inclusion
看待项目的多样性和包容性
with a more serious eye
现在真的很普遍
and I think it's great that there are people at Apache
我很高兴人们在Apache
that are taking up that question again
再次提出这个问题
because it is a monoculture in some regards
因为这在某些方面是一种单一文化
and it'd be nice to see it
并且我很希望能看到
you know blossom in a thousand more directions
百花齐放的现象
which is what diversity has
而这正是多样性
the promise of doing about it
有望实现的
we have to be careful
我们必须小心
not to lose the things that make Apache special so
不要失去Apache的特殊之处
the word meritocracy for instance
例如meritocracy一词
has not always been popular among
在在多样性和包容性活动人士群体中
diversity and inclusion activists
并不总是很流行
but Apache is very much something that runs on
但是Apache（在meritocracy方面）可以说是非常成功
shall we say a du cracy
you know you get more clout in the community by doing things
你知道你只要做事情就能在社区中获得更多的影响力
in the early days, when there were just 30 of us 50 of us
在早期阶段,那时我们的参与者只有30个，50个
a hundred of us
或者100个，
it was very easy to communicate the vision
交流想法并且对Apache是​​什么以及成功意味着什么
and have a shared vision of what Apache was and what success meant
达成共识是很容易的
as we grow
随着我们（社区）不断成长壮大
you know we now have 800 members
我们现在有约800个成员
we have something like 8,000 contributors to our individual projects
我们的各个项目总共约有8,000个贡献者
and many of them no longer
其中许多人
really have a vision of what Apache is supposed to be
不再真正了解Apache应该是什么样子
they're participating in
他们只是参与
a software project
某个软件项目
because it's part of their job
因为这是他们工作的一部分
or because that particular project is their hobby
或者因为那个项目是他们的业余爱好
but the larger vision of the foundation is at risk of getting diluted
但Apache基金会更大的愿景正面临被淡化的风险
ASF is now 20 years old in a best possible world
Apache基金会如今已经20岁了
it'll become 40 years old
慢慢地，它会到40岁
and it'll become 60 years old
会到60岁
somewhere in that timeframe
到某个时候
none of the people involved at the beginning
最初的那些贡献者们将不再会
will be involved anymore
继续贡献
they'll be dead
他们总会老去
that'll be true for me too at some point sooner or later
迟早有一天我也将会老去
there will be other people doing this
将会有其他人继续贡献
now
现在
I wouldn't want to
我并不想
impose too much exactly what I think or what we think on them
强加给他们太多我的想法或者我们的想法
but I would hope that
但是我希望
we could communicate what really was good about us have
从现在开始到到未来的20年，我们可以交流，
20 years ago, 10 years ago,now to them
告诉他们我们在20年前、10年前、现在
20 years from now
所拥有的那些好东西
so that they can carry that forward interpreting it
这样他们就可以在20年后的
as the world is 20 years from now
可能与现在大不相同的世界里
which may be very different than it is now
继续拥有它、诠释它
I talked about that meeting back in 1998
回想1998年的那次会议
where we had all the developers for the Apache web server
当时我们所有Apache web server这个项目的开发人员
in one place at one time
在同一时间出现在同一地点
and my concern at that point
当时我就担心
was that we had all the developers
我们所有的开发人员
in one place at one time
同一时间在同一地点的话
and if something it was to happen some natural disaster
如果发生一些自然灾害
or we all ate the wrong bad sushi that
或者我们都吃了变质的食物
that community would then go away
那么Apache 就不复存在了
than the I wasn't worried about the code
我并不担心这个项目的代码（是否会消失）
because the code was already on tens of
因为这些代码已经在世界各地的
thousands of servers around the world
成千上万的服务器上了
I was really worried that we'd lose the people
我真正担心的是失去人
who shared the same core values
失去那些拥有共同的核心价值观
that same mission
相同的使命的人
and that's what would have defined success
而这些才是成功的关键
the project success is based on on the people rather than the code
项目的成功是基于人的而不是基于代码的
and that's pretty much what comes about by
而这就是
the Apache way
Apache之道
[Music]
a lot of people ask us what the Apache Way is all about
很多人问我们Apache Way到底是什么
it's one of our core principles at Apache
这是我们Apache的核心准则之一
much like this path that I'm on
就像我刚才走的这条路
it guides us in a specific direction
它引导我们
that we like to go
朝着我们想要去的方向前进
but a lot of people have different ideas of what the Apache Way is about
但是很多人对Apache Way的含义有不同的看法
we'll get a chance to
我们会找机会
talk to some those people to
与这些人聊聊
get their impressions
听一听他们对Apache way的解读
the Apache way ,it has many version of truth
Apache Way有很多种说法
and people have different meaning and interpretation to the Apache Way
人们对Apache Way的定义和解释不同
Apache Way is a little bit like zem
永久的方式有点像zem，
you cannot really put it in just a few sentences
你无法只用几句话就可以描述清楚
you kind of have to feel it
你需要去感受它
it's interesting
非常有趣的是
if you ask 10 people how they would describe the Apache way
如果让10个人告诉你什么是Apache way
you'd probably get about 11 answers
你可能会得到11种答案
the Apache Way is all about Community Over Code
Apache Way就是Community Over Code （社区胜于代码）
Apache Way is Community Over Code
Apache Way是Community Over Code
Community Over Code, Community Over Code
code doesn't manage itself,yet
代码无法自己管理自己，至少现在不行
it might in the future
将来可能会吧
for me it's all about communication and community
对我来说，（Apache Way）就是交流与社区的一切
I'm not really sure if that's the right answer
我不确定这是否是正确的答案
we say Community Over Code
我们说Community Over Code
but it's not a not something we just just make up
但这不是我们凭空捏造的说法
it really is the most important
因为Apache软件基金会
part of the Apache Software Foundation is the people
最重要的部分就是社区的人
I know that a lot of people
我知道很多人说过
have said things like community over code
诸如社区胜于代码之类的话
and so on
but I think it's easier to express it in actual verbs and nouns together
但我认为用一些具体的动词、名词一起表达更容易理解
so we as people come together
比如我们聚在一起
we have some communal interest
我们有着共同的兴趣
as such we we build a structure together
因此，我们一起构建了一个组织
that allows us to work together
能够让我们能够一起努力工作、
that allows us to communicate
能够让我们一起互相交流
allows us to bring in new people and build software together
能够让我们吸引新的朋友加入进来并一起开发软件
now this is definitely
（通过上面的描述）现在就很明显了
not the fastest way to build software
这不是构建软件最快的方法
but it's a remarkably sustainable way
但这是一种非常可持续的方式
if you have a great community
如果你有一个很棒的社区
if you managed to build a vibrant, self-sustaining,self-governing community
如果你设法建立一个充满活力、自我维持、自我管理的社区
your code will come
你的代码自会到来
even if your community started with maybe not
即使您的社区开始时可能没有
the best code base out there
最好的代码库
but the community itself is great
但是社区本身很棒
you will go through a refactoring process of that code base
你们就会通过代码的不断重构，
and arrive at version 2
升级成2.0版本
version 3
乃至3.0版本
that would be much better than what you started with
最终比开始时的代码要好得多
but the other way around is
但是反过来
absolutely not the case
绝对不是这样
we focus on everything being done on public mailing lists
我们所有工作都放在公开邮件列表上
so both are clean
这样非常整洁
and our dirty laundry
我们项目的缺点都显而易见
it's basically out on the clothesline for everyone to see
每个人都可以看到
but I think that's healthy
我认为这是对我们有益的
we have this fascination with mailing lists which is very very old
我们队这种非常古老的邮件列表的交流方式十分迷恋
and why can't you use
但是为什么不能
you know something more immediate say slack
即时的通讯软件（比如slack）来交流呢
for example, what's that
because we are, you know, old timers stuck in the mud
那是因为我们都是老古董了
who just love mailing lists
只喜欢邮件列表
it's because we want something which is asynchronous
那是因为我们想要实现异步通讯
the ASF also it's very good at building bridges
ASF很善于搭建桥梁
across time zones
来跨越时区
sir is there use of asynchronous communication for important decisions
他们使用异步的通讯模式来对重要的事情进行决策
there's a 72-hour window
比如对于决策都会有72小时的时间窗口
where people have time to participate in a vote
用于人们投票参与
for instance
but it's also good at building bridges
此外这种交流模式也很自然地搭建了
across time into history like
一个跨越时间历史的桥梁
if you're wondering today what happened
比如说如果您现在想知道
in the httpd server project more than 20 years ago
20多年前httpd服务器项目中发生了什么
you can still find that out
你仍然可以发现
because all of the communication is archived
因为所有通信记录都已存档
is searchable and has stable links to it
并且能够被搜索，还有稳定的链接可访问
you know, so looking at it ,that way,
这么看起来的话，
it's not mailing lists, which are important
并不是说邮件列表这种方式是重要的
it's making sure that
真正重要的是
whatever communication mechanism medium that you use
无论使用哪种通讯手段，都要确保
doesn't disenfranchise anyone
不能剥夺任何人参与的权利
and enables anyone and everyone who has a
并且能使任何
passing interest to be involved in the communication
有浓厚兴趣的人都可以参与到交流中
and see what's going on to be able to do that
并能让大家看到其他人要做什么事情
in a way that
makes them equal peers to everyone else
让大家人人平等
everyone's considered equal
每个人的想法都是同等重要的
everyone can contribute
每个人都可以贡献
there's no one there who gets to decide because I'm the the boss of the project
没有哪个人能自己做出决断，因为没有人是项目的boss，
I decide which feature gets included of
没有人能决定哪个功能要保留
which feature does not get included
哪个功能不保留
nobody really cares about who you are
没有人真正在乎你是谁
sort of it's about what you do
而（他们）在乎的是你到底做了什么
to me ,meritocracy is about building that
对我来说，精英管理就是要经受时间考验来
credibility over time
建立信誉
and that the community recognizes you for those efforts
社区最终会因为你的努力而认可你，
the people who contribute a lot
为社区做出了许多贡献的人
whether it's go door or other things
无论他是谁
receive some rewards
都应该得到鼓励
but yet when it comes time to make a decision
但当要做决策时
no one of them's
没有人有更大的话语权
regardless of their merit
无论他们贡献有多大
has a much larger voice than any other
the people who do the work should have a say
为项目做贡献的人都应该有发言权
in how projects work, and that seems fair to me
来决定项目如何运作,我觉得这是公平的
that's also the connected idea
另外一个观点是贡献是不会过期的
that merit doesn't expire so if you did
所以说，如果您
something 20 years ago and earned some
在20年前做了某件事，并因此赢得
right for it that that doesn't expire
了一些权利，那么这些权利就不会过期
I'm not sure if that's almost a good thing
我不确定这是否总是一件好事
if a committer needs to take a
如果代码提交者需要
year off to go and do something
花一年的时间去做其他的事
then they can come back and
然后他们又回到社区
they still have exactly the same weight
他们在社区中仍然拥有和他们离开前一样
and right to speak in the communities
的份量和发言权
they had before they left
I think those things are important
我认为这些事情很重要
and it's a big part of how it actually works the way
这是它实际运作方式的重要组成部分
it doesn't why it's been so successful
而不是为什么它如此成功的原因
consistently， the apache way make sure
始终如一地，Apache方式确保了
that it does work out well
它能很好地运转
and that's why companies trust apache software
这就是为什么公司信任Apache软件
the leadership you will find an apache
你会发现Apache
are the people that inspire others
是在鼓励其他人（参与进来）
that's the leadership at apache
这就是Apache的领导力
we inspire each other， and we're all leaders at some point
我们互相激励，我们在某个时候都是领导者
and you know the seat just changes
大家只是座位变了而已
I mean the core governance processes of Apache
我的意思是说：Apache的核心治理方法
are very well documented in the form of bylaws
都以章程的形式记录得很好
and all that kind of stuff
和各种类型的记录
figuring out
弄清楚如何向全世界的人教导
how to broadly educate the world about how to work this way
如何以这种方式进行工作
is a challenge for everybody
这对每个人都是一个挑战
and all I can say is as more smart people keep
而我只能说，随着越来越聪明的人
coming to this community
不断来到这个社区
we have a chance not only to help further define that
我们不仅有机会进一步定义这一点
but to continuously update it
而且可以推陈出新
update it for a world that again is much different this year
就像今年与20年前相比
than it was 20 years ago
大不相同一样
you know we thought a lot about how do we sustain the foundation
您知道我们对如何维持基金会进行了很多思考
kind of as Greg Stein , you know
就像格雷格·斯坦（Greg Stein）
had often put it was
所说的那样
you know, think about the foundation
想一想基金会如果
living for hundred years and what does that mean
生存上百年，那将意味着什么
and it means growing the
这意味着不断发展
foundation and providing a stable base
基金会并提供稳定的基础
to ensure that success. In a way we did
来确保成功。这其中的一种方式
that was an Apache Incubator project
就是Apache 孵化项目
which is how we found the next
这是我们找到下一代
generation of Apache software projects
Apache软件项目的方法
she think that we can teach everyone
她认为我们可以教大家
to be good playmates basically and that's
成为优秀玩家
that's what the incubation process is
这就是孵化的过程
all the，let's say "rules" on
现存所有项目推荐的"规则"
recommendations that exist have a reason
都有其理由
to be and the reason is sustainability
那就是未来
of the projects in the futures
项目的可持续性
if your project
如果您的项目
is only driven by a unique company
仅由唯一的公司驱动
is not an Apache project, it's a company project
那它就是只是一个公司项目，而不是Apache项目
so during the incubation process
因此在孵化过程中
you have to show that you have different users
您必须证明您的项目拥有来自
from different background
不同背景的不同用户
I think that the incubation process is a key part of
我认为孵化过程
why Apache remains successful
是Apache保持成功的关键部分
it has to do with with dealing with scaling
这决定了我们如何发展
growing this culture
发展这种文化
not just imposing it upon people
不是将其强加于人
but helping them understand why it matters
而是帮助大家了解其重要性
and bringing them into the family
将他们带入（Apache）家庭
and establishing those relationships
并建立这种关系
to me, it feels that, ASF presents
在我看来，ASF向世界展示
this really amazing lesson to the world
了非常棒的经验
which I would love to see spread out, you know
我很乐意看到，将它传播到
to even schools, universities right
甚至是学校、大学中
because if you think about it
因为如果您思考一下就会发现
ASF presents a model of collaboration
ASF提出的这种合作模式
that can not only be applied within corporations
不仅在公司内部适用
interestingly enough, by the way
有趣的是，顺便说一下
a lot of corporations, these days
如今许多公司
have this notion of “inner-source”
都有"内部开源"这一概念
basically saying well
基本上来说
even though we may not be contributing to the open source
即使我们因为法律原因
you know, because of the legal reason
或者公司政策原因
or just, you know, corporate reasons
不能将项目贡献给开源社区
inside of the corporation itself
但在公司内部
we will behave, our engineers will behave
我们的工程师的协作方式
as though we're practicing open source, right
就像我们在参与开源项目一样
so that engineers can stop working in the
这样，工程师们就不再只是
salt mines of siloed over specialized teams
在单一团队中孤零零的工作
and become the full flowering of
而是可以全身心的参与
what it could be, which is collaborative
到协作中，成为
members of cooperative that create software
共同创造软件的一员
but it doesn't stop there
但是它并不仅限于此
you can actually manage to get the same model
您实际上可以将相同的模型
and apply to all sorts of different areas of human endeavor right
应用于人类协作的各种不同领域。
you can build your local organization
例如假设您需要建立一个本地组织
that is trying to enact change
来实施
a political change, for example
诸如政治变革的变更
in a real world you can build it
那么您完全可以通过使用
through the same set of principles
和我们建立Apache软件基金会
that we utilize to build Apache Software Foundation
相同的一套原则来对其进行构建
it doesn't have to be software development
这套机制适用的场景不限于软件开发
it could be anything, you could be building a house
它可以适用任意（需要协作的）场景，比如盖房子
when people talk about Apache
当人们谈论Apache
and the Apache way
或者Apache之道时
they think "oh yeah software development"
他们认为“哦这是关于软件开发的”
but it's not
但其实并不是
it's a social way of working, a social way
这是一种社会协同的工作方式
a collaborative way of doing something together
一种共同做某事的协作方式
in a way that you know
以一种
you can learn from other people
人们可以相互学习的方式
and you get the best of all the ideas
并且您可以从所有创意中得到最大的收获
that's the beauty of it, that's the beauty of the solution
那就是它的美妙之处，是这种解决方案的美妙之处
hundreds and hundreds of years, where
在数百年的历史中
knowledge was used to generate money
知识都是用来赚钱的
and the only success factor in society
而社会上唯一成功的因素
is how much money my company making
就是我的公司赚了多少钱
I think that the ASF
但我认为ASF
has proven that even without making money
已经证明即使没有赚钱
we really did have a humongous impact
我们也对这个世界运转的方式
in the way in which the world runs
产生了巨大的影响
it would be really cool
那将真的很酷
if people could share without feeling like they're gonna lose for sharing
如果人们可以共享而不会觉得自己会因为共享而输掉
I came from a bit of a sports background
我有一点儿运动员背景
where it was more win-lose type of an environment
那偏向于一种非赢即输的环境
being able to be an environment
在一个
where competing with people and collaborating with people
与人竞争但同时也与人合作的环境
actually creates win-win situations
可以创造双赢局面
has been something
I've learned from participating in open source
是我从参与开源当中学到的
and made me realize that
并使我认识到
this is how most of companies and humanity should work
这就是大多数公司和人类应该采取但工作方式
one of the things we're seeing nowadays
我们（从Apache中）看到的一件事是
is that the lessons learned inside of IT
从IT方面学到的经验教训
as far as how to create successful open-source projects
以及如何创建成功的开源项目
but most importantly
但最重要的是
how to create successful open source communities
Apache之道不仅在如何创建成功的开源社区方面
of which the Apache Way is most probably the best example
是最好的例子
of that, is starting to make inroads in other areas
而且这种方式也开始进军到其他领域
the success of open source is going to expand beyond IT
开源的成功将超越IT
is going to beyond the software development in ecosystem
超越生态系统中的软件开发
and so we're seeing a lot of the tenants of successful open source
我们看到了许多成功开源的客户
a lot of the means of Apache Way transcend the IT community
许多Apache之道的方法超越了IT社区本身
and I think that's an incredible heritage
我认为这是对于我们创造的运动
for the movement we've created
不可思议的传承
the use cases that get me excited are the ones
使我兴奋的用例是
that are about trying to address any one of those 260
即试图解决260个
different sustainable development goals out there
不同的可持续发展目标中的任何一个
right
if we're going to have a carbon trading market
如果我们要建立一个碳交易市场
we're going to need a distributed ledger system
那么我们将需要一个分布式的分类帐系统
to be able to do that on a global scale
以便能够在全球范围内做到这一点
if we're going to eliminate child labour in mines
如果我们要消除矿山
or on fishing boats or in other industries
渔船或其他行业中的童工
it's going to be through technologies like this
我们将通过像这样的技术来实现
Fineract is a project
Fineract是一个
that supports microfinance institutionsand giving out loans
为小额信贷机构提供支持并发放贷款
and tracking savings for the poorest of the poor
并为最穷的穷人持续提供救助的项目
so
因此
it's very rewarding to be able to make these services available to the poor
能够将这些服务提供给穷人是非常有益的
because if you don't have savings
因为如果您没有储蓄
if you don't have loans, if you don't have remittances
没有贷款，没有汇款
that's money transfers
也就是转账
then you don't have contact to the global economy
那你就没有接触全球经济的途径
and you can't profit when your boat doesn't rise, when everybody else's boat rises
当你的船不升起，而其他人的船升起时，你无法获利
in the case of this project
在此项目中
you're connecting the empowerment of the poorest of the poor
您将（帮助）最贫穷者的能力
with the empowerment of the software developers
与软件开发人员的能力联系在一起
and you're doing both of them in the context of a community
并且在社区的背景下同时做这两件事情
so
因此
it's really wonderful parallels between open source software and microfinance
这是（实施）开源软件（开发）和小额信贷之间的完美并行
being part of that it just gave me a great feeling
参与其中使我觉得
that we've been able to change the world for the better
我们已经能够改善世界，这是一种非常美妙的感觉
a lot of our software helps developing countries
我们开发的很多软件都帮助了发展中国家
the great strides the world has made today
当今世界取得的巨大进步
in the last 20 years of globalization
在全球化的最近20年中
with the developing countries growing and advancing
发展中国家不断发展壮大
and providing better living conditions and better economic advancement for its populations
并为其人民提供了更好的生活条件和更好的经济发展
that's a result of the free software movement
这都是自由软件运动发展的结果
and Apache had a big hand in that
而Apache在这方面发挥了很大的作用
I feel very strongly
我非常强烈得认为
the only thing that will save us as a species
（Apache之道是）唯一能帮助我们这个物种
from our own internal greed and hatred
摆脱内部的贪婪和仇恨
and the distance that we put between human hearts
以及人心之间距离的方式
and I occasionally am chided
我偶尔会被嘲笑
because I am very sensitive person and have thin skin
因为我非常敏感，脸皮薄
then they say you need thicker skin
然后他们说我需要脸皮厚一些
thicker skin puts more distance between human hearts
脸皮厚会让人心更有距离
it allows more space for "not like me"
它为不喜欢我的人提供了更多空间
it allows more space for "us versus them"
它为人们互相对立提供了更多的空间
and that will be our undoing not just as technologists but as a species
这将导致我们，不仅是作为技术专家，而且是作为一个物种，的失败
and we are at a crucial point in our evolution
我们正处在发展的关键时刻
I believe where we need to start
我相信我们需要开始
caring more about each other and less about profit
关心彼此而不是见利忘义
and the Apache way voices one part of that
Apache之道呼吁了部分关于这方面的内容
I think in a very powerful way
我认为这是一种非常强大的方式
when we put community above code
当我们将社区置于代码之上
that gives us the opportunity to have a place
这使我们有机会拥有一个地方
where people can be passionate about solving other people's problems
使人们有激情去解决其他人的问题
and that is one element of good empathy
这是让大家互相理解的一个关键要素
teaching people that at the end of the day
告诉人们，归根结底
what we're really here for
我们真正要做的是
is to leave the campground better than we found it
离开营地时要比我们发现的时候更好
always create more value than you try to monetize
始终创造出比营利更多的价值
this is how I give back to the world
这就是我回馈世界的方式
when you're volunteering directly in something local
当您直接在当地从事志愿工作时
you are making an impact on the lives that are at the event you're at
您会对当地的生活产生影响
but when I volunteer at Apache
但是当我在Apache志愿工作时
I'm making an impact on the world
我就在世界上产生了影响
as right now you know
目前而言
there's a lot of criticism of the Internet community and technology companies
对互联网社区和科技公司的批评很多
and such for you know
如您所知道得那样
throwing up grand visions of a brighter tomorrow
他们提出了美好的宏伟愿景
and behind the scenes
但在幕后
selling eyeballs to venture capitalists
抢占资金风口
right you know and milking that for profit
您知道的那是为了营利
I believe
但我相信
there's a lot of people though who really genuinely recognize what's wrong in the world
同时也有很多人真正地认识到世界上的问题
and our technologists want to use technology to fix that
而我们的技术人员则希望使用技术来解决这一问题。
trying to predict the future is coming up hard
很难预测未来
my normal quote on that is
对此我经常引用
the best way to predict the future is to invent it
"预测未来的最好方法是创造它"
so
因此
rather than trying to guess where we'll go with the Apache Software Foundation
与其猜测ASF将怎样发展
we should instead kind of do the things that need doing right now
不如做好当下
and see where that takes us
来看我们能取得什么结果
I hope that as Greg Stein likes to say that
我希望就像Greg Stein (Apache软件基金会主席) 所说的那样
we're still around in 50 years
我们大概还有50年的寿命
that we have found a way to continue our culture
我们找到了一种继续我们的文化的方式
a way to continue to bring on new generations
一种继续培养下一代的方式
that we've created a place where people feel comfortable leaving
我们创造了一个让人们放心离开的地方
and that may sound a little bit weird
这听起来可能有点怪异
but what I mean is that
但是我的意思是
I can feel that I can step out of my position
我感觉到我可以放心的退休
and know that
并且相信
we'll still be going strong with a new generation of passionate people
新一代充满激情的人可以让Apache变得更加强大
being open to the new types of technology and the new projects that are evolving
我们一直对新技术和持续更新的项目保持开放
one of the things that's been really exciting about the foundation is that
关于基金会最令人兴奋的一件事就是
we seem to be a place where a lot of new technology comes from
这里是许多新技术产生的地方
we've been at the forefront of creating entire industry
我们一直走在整个行业的最前沿
and that's really exciting for me
这让我真的很兴奋
as a technologist as a big geek myself
我自己是一个技术专家和极客
I love being able to be part of something that is inventing entire new things
我喜欢能够参与到发明世界上从未出现过的
that the world's never seen before
全新事物的过程中
I think that in a healthy world
我认为在一个健康的世界中
corporations that benefit from using open-source or depending their business on open-source
通过使用开源或将业务依赖于开源而受益的公司
should contribute back to that in some form
应该以某种形式对开源做出贡献
whether it's through sponsorships
无论是通过赞助
or by having employees involved in the projects
或者让员工参与到开源项目
I'm here, what can I do
我在这里，我能做什么
well ,there's a million things you can do
嗯，有一百万件事你可以做
I think it's important
我认为这很重要
that people outside the Apache Software Foundation realize that
ASF之外的人员认识到
they can become part of the foundation which don't rely on coding
编写代码并不是成为ASF成员的唯一方式
I don't code anymore
我已经不再编程了
I work on handling security issues
我致力于处理安全性问题
and there's plenty of things you can do within the ASF which don't rely on coding
您可以在ASF中做很多不依赖编码的事情
everyone has a contribution to make
每个人都可以做出贡献
right, whether it's lines of code, of course
无论是代码
but it could also be art work
还是艺术作品
or it could also be documentation
或者文档
or it could be mentoring or just simple advice
也可以是指导或简单的建议
I build software on my own
我有独立开发的软件
that is trivial, it has no great value
那是微不足道的，没有太大的价值
I do it alone because there is no reason for a community there
我一个人做是因为没有理由在那里建立社区，
but I also build software
但我也开发了一些
which changes people's lives
可以改变人们的生活
which saves lives, which protects people
拯救生命，保护人民
which helps people build medicines
帮助人们制造药物
helps people build cars, helps people build spacecraft
帮助人们建造汽车和航天器的软件
and that software really does deserve a longer life
这些软件值得更长的生命周期
and does deserve a community around it
也值得建立社区来维护
the people in the ASF tend to soak like want to solve problems
ASF成员沉浸于解决问题
they don't go talk like go doom and gloom and fit and worried and oh
他们不去谈论厄运，阴郁，健康，担心等等
it's not working and oh we can't do anything else
他们不会抱怨"哦这样不行"，"哦没办法了"
and oh Jesus Christ we have to rewrite things
或者"哦天哪我们只能重写了"
but they solve like, tend to solve like, solve things like
相反的，他们倾向于解决问题，更像是
okay, I will do whatever to solve this
好吧，我会不惜一切代价来解决这个问题
everybody is always up to interesting projects
我们每个人都很愿意从事有趣的项目
and always
并且
in a fashion of learning, in kind of
以一种学习的方式，就像
oh hey you're working on that thing
哦，嘿，你在做那件事
hey maybe there's a way I can leverage that
嘿，也许我可以利用一种方法优化它
apache is really good at bringing people together
apache真的很擅长将人们召集在一起
and letting them work together
让他们一起工作
without companies getting in the way
而不需要公司的介入
you definitely don't need to be rigid hierarchical top-down to get cool things done
我们不需要严格地自上而下地方式，也能完成非常酷的事情
Apache itself is kind of intertwined my life for the last 25 years
在过去的25年中，我的人生与Apache息息相关
everything about what I am now and what I've done professionally personally
我个人的一切成就
has been because of Apache
都与Apache有关
I found myself (in) Apache Software Foundation, I see wow this is my home
我在ASF实现了个人价值，我把ASF看作是我的家
and I want to do not just trade my time for money
我不仅要用我的时间来换钱
I want to do something bigger than you know that
我还想做更大的事情
it's not only my job it's also my passion
这不仅是我的工作，也是我的激情
it doesn't matter what language you speak
无论你使用什么语言
where you come from
无论你来自何方
but Apache is there to help encourage people from all over the world
Apache帮助并鼓励全世界的人
to continue working together for the betterment of mankind
为人类的美好未来共同努力
if I could travel back in time and tell me
如果能时光回溯，我会告诉我自己
Allison is like trying to get into this thing earlier
Allison你会想尽早加入ASF
because it has many advantages
因为它有很多优点
if you want to be part just jump in I mean it's pretty easy
如果你想参与其中，那就来吧，我是说加入进来其实很简单
so come forward here and be part of the Apache Software Foundation
欢迎到来并加入ASF
[Music]
apache has done so much over the past decades
过去，apache做出了很大贡献
we expect to continue to do so for decades to come
我们希望将来亦如此
and will continue to serve trillions and trillions
我们将继续大众服务
[Music]
[Applause]